# Brian M Hofmeister

https://brianmhofmeister.com • brian@brianmhofmeister.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/brianhofmeister/

With over 20 years of diverse professional software and leadership experience, I bring a unique perspective to every project. Customer and product focus, honest and open communication, empathy, and collaboration are my core values. My passion is creating robust, reliable, and effective software; I strive to build the right thing, and to build the thing right. For additional project details please visit my LinkedIn page, to which a link is provided above.

# **Experience**

HelpSystems, LLC

October, 2017 - May, 2020

Software Engineer II

Backup, Recovery, and Media Services for IBM i

- IBM Intellectual Property Partnership, HelpSystems provided development and L3 technical support.
- Developed solutions for customer reported problems and product requirements, assisted with development of custom build tools.
- Participated in daily scrum, agile planning and retrospective discussions.
- Worked with IBM Global Support teams to investigate and resolve customer issues, collaborated with IBM global translation centers for Translation Verification Testing (TVT), helped to resolve issues
- Skills Applied: C/C++, RPG, Java, CL, bash scripting

Digital River

June 2012 - September 2017

Engineering Manager

Teams

Skills Acquired/Applied

- Developer Productivity
- Client Integrations
- Java
- XML/SOAP/XSLT
- REST

- AWS EC2/IAM/S3/ELB
- OpenStack
- Docker

### Accomplishments

- Led migration effort from CVS to Git and GitHub Enterprise
- Co-led roll-out of source controlled database schema model, tools, and processes
- Designed, developed, and support backing services for application supporting QA and Compliance teams
- Early adoption of and support to teams in using AWS, OpenStack, and Docker technologies
- Automated processes for application security team, release management team, and functional teams
- Lead the administration and support of GitHub Enterprise, Jenkins, GoCD, Nexus Professional, Artifactory, SonarQube, and SmartBear Collaborator
- Lead the management and support of continuous integration for flagship commerce platform
- Embraced lean software development principles and "Scrumban" approach to delivery
- Advocate for Continuous Delivery
- Delivered client integrations projects using in-house developed integration framework based on SOAP/XML and XSLT

Mayo Clinic

September 2011 - June 2012

Senior Analyst/Programmer

Radiology Operational Systems/Integrations and Interfaces support team

- Connected Radiology systems to other hospital systems throughout the Mayo Enterprise
- HL7 integrations using in-house developed integration engine.

This resumé is private and confidential. It is made available to you for evaluation of the applicant and must not be shared with anyone outside of your company.

# Brian M Hofmeister

https://brianmhofmeister.com • brian@brianmhofmeister.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/brianhofmeister/

# Experience (continued)

## **International Business Machines Corporation**

March 1999 – June 2011

Staff Software Engineer

#### Products/Teams

- IBM i Access Family
- Integrated Application Server for IBM i
- WebSphere Partner Gateway
- WebSphere Business Integration for IBM i
- Programming Support Team (PST)
- Backup, Recovery, and Media Services (BRMS)

# Skills Acquired/Applied

- Java
- RPG
- C/C++
- CL

#### Accomplishments

- Led small project teams, world-wide services training coordination, and global translation verification testing
  efforts.
- Developed software installation projects for Java and Windows
- Supported software globalization and accessibility testing
- Quality assurance: test case development, test case execution, test planning, defect management.
- Extensive level 3 support experience, solving problems reported by internal and external customers.
- Developed deep expertise of BRMS integration with IBM i operating system via Tape Management System system exit point program interface.
- Developed new feature support for Hierarchical File System and Independent Auxiliary Storage Pools.

## **BORN** Information Services, Inc.

August 1996 - March 1999

Technical Consultant

# Teams

- Open Client/Server Business Unit
- AS/400 Business Unit

## Skills Acquired/Applied

- RPG
- Synon 2E
- PowerBuilder

## Accomplishments

- Application development in support of customer service, finance and manufacturing.
- Developed Synon 2E interfaces to vendor ERP, EDI and data warehouse solutions.
- Developed RPG connector for barcode scanner in support of Kanban inventory flow for manufacturing floor
- Gathered user requirements; developed functional design specifications per client standards; delivered user training; mentor to client development staff team members.
- Developed and maintained PowerBuilder applications.

#### International Business Machines, Inc.

June 1995 - June 1996

Software Engineer Intern

- Query Optimization Team for DB2 for IBM i
- Skills Developed/Used: DB2 for IBM i, SQL, CL

#### Education

Minnesota State University, Mankato Bachelor of Science, cum laude Computer Science Mankato, MN July 1996

This resumé is private and confidential. It is made available to you for evaluation of the applicant and must not be shared with anyone outside of your company.